# Kolten Edward

# Software Engineer

8076 Decatur St, Westminster, 80031 • koltenedward@proton.me • 720-515-7373 koltenedward.com • github.com/kdten • in/koltenedward

#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

3+ years experience as a Software Engineer. Successfully reduced cross-platform app development time by 31%. Utilized TDD-approach with 3-5 unit tests per function. Raised defects in code reviews, leading to increased software quality and regulatory compliance.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Typescript, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS
Frontend React, Redux, Next[S, Playwright, Tailwind CSS

Backend AWS, NodeJS, Express, Mocha, Chai, MongoDB, GraphQL, RESTful API, Stripe

Tools Visual Studio Code, GitHub, Docker, Postman, Git, npm, CI/CD

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

100DevsLos Angeles, CASoftware Engineer08/2022 - Current

Technologies: Typescript, ESLint, React, Redux, NextJS, NodeJS, Express, GraphQL, AWS

- Accomplished a 31% reduction in time spent on cross-platform app development by utilizing Ionic React.
- Independently responsible for building 7 new features, and maintaining 10 others features, with 4 legacy.
- Debugged and added features to production-level codebase utilizing React, Typescript, and GraphQL.
- Identified and fixed defects, increasing software quality and ensuring legal and regulatory compliance.
- Increased code deployment speed by 30% in the first three months through introduction of optimized CI/CD processes.

Frontend Engineer 03/2021 - 08/2022

Technologies: JavaScript, Handlebars, Pug, Bootstrap, jQuery, AJAX, ESLint

- Developed and maintained user-friendly web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, ensuring cross-browser compatibility and performance optimization.
- Implemented responsive web design principles to create seamless user experiences across various devices and screen sizes, enhancing accessibility and engagement.
- Enhanced user engagement and marketability by implementing moving WEBM backgrounds, creating an immersive and visually appealing UI and UX collaboratively with the client.
- Conducted comprehensive testing using tools like Jest and Selenium, ensuring robustness and reliability of front-end components.

2017-2021: Supervisor in various depts at Costco Wholesale

#### **PROJECTS**

#### CouponCatch - couponcatchapp.com

03/2023 - Current

Technologies: Typescript, Ionic React, NextJS, NodeJS, Express, Firebase, Document AI, Stripe

- Developed and implemented MVC architecture in Node Express backend, resulting in 50% improvement in application scalability.
- Streamlined front-end and back-end communication with RESTful web services, resulting in 100% accuracy.
- Employed Cypress into development workflow for unit testing, reducing debugging time and achieving 76% test
  coverage across the front-end, ensuring robust and reliable code.
- Streamlined user signup process by implementing Firebase Authentication, reducing development time & enhancing security.

## CarHub - nextjscar-rental.vercel.app

07/2019 - 08/2020

Technologies: Typescript, Ionic React, NextJS, NodeJS, Express, Firebase, Document AI, Stripe

 Increased Google Lighthouse SEO score from 79 to 100 using Next.js SSR, resulting in improved user accessibility.

- Modernized the CSS with Tailwind CSS, streamlining the styling process over traditional per-component CSS files, resulting in a 41% reduction in development time and a more maintainable and scalable codebase.
- Consumed Rapid API for vehicle images, adhering to RESTful API best practices, which enabled real-time content delivery, improving user engagement and experience.
- Implemented a mobile-first design strategy using Next.js and Tailwind CSS, ensuring the CarHub application delivers a seamless, responsive user experience across all devices, leading to an increase in mobile user retention

### Streamr - kdten.github.io/music-app

05/2023 - 06/2023

Technologies: Typescript, Ionic React, NextJS, NodeJS, Express, Firebase, Document AI, Stripe

- Increased efficiency by choosing Vite for React development, resulting in 42% faster build times and leaner configuration.
- Enhanced user control and interaction with the application by integrating AudioSession API for hands-free experience.
- Utilized Redux state management to provide a customizable listening experience.

#### **EDUCATION**

Associate of Arts, North Iowa Area Community College, Mason City, IA